<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title/><link>/</link><description>Recent content on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>/pages/lectures/week-6/practical-sound-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/lectures/week-6/practical-sound-design/</guid><description>Guns We can&amp;rsquo;t go out to a range and record ourselves, so our next best thing is to piece together something realistic from sound effects libraries. It&amp;rsquo;s our job to take these recordings and to make them sound like what people think guns sound like. More exciting and explosive, instead of pops like firecrackers.
We can break the sound down into the following elements transient, body, thump, tail, foley or mechanical sounds, and bullet/shells.</description></item><item><title>Game Sound Database</title><link>/pages/database/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/database/</guid><description/></item><item><title>intro to unity</title><link>/pages/lectures/week-2-the-roll-of-audio-in-interactive-and-immersive-environments/wednesday-9-1/intro-to-unity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/lectures/week-2-the-roll-of-audio-in-interactive-and-immersive-environments/wednesday-9-1/intro-to-unity/</guid><description>Start with a new scene
Explore the main windows
Hierarchy window scene view inspector project game view play mode navigate using toolbar
Pan: Select the Hand tool in the Toolbar, and click and drag in the Scene view to move your view. Zoom: Holding Alt (Windows) or Option (macOS), right-click and drag in the Scene view to zoom. Orbit: Holding Alt (Windows) or Option (macOS), left-click and drag to orbit around the current pivot point.</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>/pages/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/projects/</guid><description>Project 1 Add sounds to 5 GameObjects in pyramid tutorial project. Move them with the scripts you already had and listen to how the doppler effect works.
Project 2 Use sounds freesound.org to replace the sounds of the FPS project. You may need to edit the sounds from freesound, or manipulate them. Experiment with filters and effects.
Add another room using the tutorial. Add an enemy using the tutorial. Give the new enemy some sounds.</description></item><item><title>Resources</title><link>/pages/resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/resources/</guid><description>Sound Designers Mike Niederquell Lost Chocolate Lab Joe Thwaites Javier Zumer Websites Gamasutra - Audio Podcasts Game Audio Podcast Immersive Audio Podcast Software Game Engines Unity Unreal Engine bitsy Audio Engines FMOD Wwise 3d Audio Steam Audio - Immersive Audio Solutions For games and VR Tutorials Sound Librarian Conferences Interactive Music Symposium - Thursday, August 26th, 12pm - 6pm GameSoundCon - November 8-10, 2021 Online Audio Developer Conferece - November 15th &amp;amp; 16th - In-Person/Online Conference in London - November 19th - Online Workshops Example from last year Game Developers Conference - March 21-25, 2022 | San Francisco, CA</description></item><item><title>Schedule</title><link>/pages/schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/schedule/</guid><description>table { border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; } tr { border-bottom: 1px solid #ccc; } th { text-align: left; } } Week Date Topics, Assignments, Quizzes, Tests, Deadlines 1 8/23, 8/25, 8/27 Monday 8/23 Me - Dr. Carson Class introductions Name? Class year? Where are you from? What&amp;rsquo;s your favorite game or movie? Syllabus Perusall signup I will assign readings, videos, or podcasts through Perusall.</description></item><item><title>Syllabus</title><link>/pages/syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/syllabus/</guid><description>Course Prefix, Number, and Title: DAD 422 Audio Production III Advanced Techniques and MIDI Music
AKA Introduction to Immersive Game Audio
Credits: 3
University Name: Dakota State University
Academic Term/Year: Fall 2021
Last date to Drop and receive 100% refund: September 2nd, 2021
Last date to Withdraw and earn a grade of &amp;lsquo;W&amp;rsquo;: November 5th, 2021
Course Meeting Time and Location: MWF 1:00 pm – 2:40 pm TCB 209
Instructor Information: Name: Tate Carson Office: TCB 305 Email Address: Tate.</description></item><item><title>What is immersive audio?</title><link>/pages/lectures/week-1/monday-8-23/immersive-spatial/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/lectures/week-1/monday-8-23/immersive-spatial/</guid><description>Think about your favorite game or movie. What about the sounds creates a feeling of being correct or realistic? Or more simply, what do we need to recreate from real life sounds in our virtual world?
Using what we learned from the video lets analyze the following games.
Questions How do games use sound to evoke place or actions? Adaptive audio level 1: an event leads to a sound Adaptive audio level 2: replace or modify sound depending on variables Game Audio Examples Joe Thwaites - Sackboy explainer Mike Niederquell videos Transistor - Super Giant Games</description></item></channel></rss>